# Sabba Petri

telephone: 650.823.4323 github: spetri email: sabbap@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Enthusiastic and goal-driven individual with a passion in complex web application development and mobile development. Strong team collaborator and quick-learner with refined technical and personal communication skills; detail-oriented and committed to excellence in development contributions; managed multiple hats involving technical research, business requirements gathering and technical design, alongside custom software development and open source project development. Has been recognized for dedication, creativity, and leadership, as well as exceptional organizational and interpersonal skills.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### LANGUAGES

**Professional Knowledge** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Ruby

Familiar Knowledge C#, Java, C/C++

## FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES

Professional Knowledge

JS: jQuery, Backbone, Jasmine (BDD)

CSS: CSS3, SASS/LESS

Frameworks: Rails, Django

Other: ASP.NET MVC, ActiveRecord, Solr, RabbitMQ (AMQP)

#### **DATABASES**

**Professional Knowledge**Oracle, MS SQL Server MySQL, SQLite

Familiar Knowledge MongoDB, PostgreSQL

#### **OFFICE APPLICATIONS**

Professional Knowledge

Microsoft Office Suite (can type > 125 wpm) Microsoft SharePoint 2010 Microsoft Reporting Services Cisco Unified Communications Manager

Familiar Knowledge Microsoft SQL Server Integration Services

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Consultant | Technical Product Development & Design**

Sunnyvale, CA| November 2014 – Current

Working with multiple startups to elevate their business practices, developing relations with their clients to gather requirements, designing and writing specification documents, and then implementing those business needs.

- Elevated customer and vendor relations by meeting with clients in person, building relationships while interviewing and gathering requirements, and writing specs / stories for other teams.
- Fully redesigned, built, tested, and marketed company websites, based heavily on user interaction and expectations, bringing in higher traffic and sales.
- Developed core features, including a form-validation framework, multiple mathematical libraries, responsive design, heavy resource loading and server management, and more. Entirely focused on beautiful design and a more unified user experience.

# Bahá'í World Centre | Technical Product Development

Haifa, Israel | January 2014 - August 2014

The worldwide center of the Baha'i International Community, a UN-recognized NGO administrating affairs for over 184 countries and territories with over 6 million members.

- Designed business/technical workflow diagrams, based on business practices and processes, to further clarify the pressure points and advantages of core business users.
- Elicited requirements using interviews, area visits, use cases, culminating into a technical business requirements document that garnered attention from many critical vendors.
- Managed business expectations and collaborated with multiple departments and teams to transform hundreds of requirements into user stories and estimated them in an agile environment.

## Bahá'í World Centre | Applications Engineer

Haifa, Israel | September 2011 - December 2014

• Developed multiple internal web applications, C# server-side and heavy JavaScript client-side, to assist and accompany the business processes of over 200 individuals.

telephone: 415.847.8023 github: spetri email: sabbap@gmail.com

- Employed both waterfall/agile processes, i.e. test-driven development, pair programming, source code control practices (Git/SVN), and test/production deployment practices.
- Maintained and supported legacy technologies, i.e. VB6 with COM, Classic ASP websites.
- Involved in all aspects of applications, from gathering initial business requirements and producing documentation to modeling the application architecture.

## UCSC David Kirk Media Centre | Video Technician Santa Cruz, California | Fall 2008 - Winter 2011

The UCSC Media Centre supports the study and teaching of film and digital media, where students can view media from dozens of video workstations and faculty can borrow thousands of items for classroom use.

- Managed and operated a large film archive, helping patrons acquire varying films needed.
- Controlled a large environment of patrons, while providing high quality customer service.
- Organized sizable amounts of media into various databases for increased worker efficiency.

## **SPG Solar | Data Management Intern**

Novato, California | Summer 2007

SPG Solar designs, engineers, installs, and maintains commercial solar projects and markets a world-class tracker technology to solar developers and integrators around the world.

- Transferred data input from various networks into one large streamlined database to provide enhanced user familiarity and added depth for customer preferences.
- Crunched for time, categorized systems of physical files into a more accessible filing system to increase work productivity, completed a few weeks before set deadline.
- Built, benchmarked, and tested solar panel systems, as well as successfully troubleshooted many system wiring issues in the field nearly 95% of the time.

## PERSONAL EXPERIENCE

## Full Circle Learning | Volunteer Curriculum Teaching

Ethiopia, Africa | Summer 2008

• Successfully completed the Full Circle Learning curriculum with Ethiopian teachers by leading a team to contribute to a small group of schools that eventually became the leading educational schools in Ethiopia.

## Community Service | English/Arts Teacher

Bolivia, South America | Summer 2006

• Collaborated with a small team in providing successful classes for better social and work opportunities.

## Community Service | Children/Youth Teacher

Belize, Central America | Summer 2005

• Helped raise moral capacities in young children through teaching children's classes daily.

## EDUCATION

# University of California Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, CA (June 2011)

- ➤ Bachelor of Arts major in Computer Science, focus in software engineering
- ➤ Bachelor of Arts major in History of Art and Visual Culture

# ADDITIONAL TRAINING AND SKILLS

## ITIL Foundational Course, Babbage Simmel

Received ITIL Foundation Certification

# Business Analysis: Eliciting and Writing Effective Requirements, L.B. Associates

## Skills & Hobbies

• Performing classical piano, participating in coding challenges, building puzzles/IKEA furniture, travelling, sports, strategy board games

#### Languages

• Fluent in English, conversational in Persian and Spanish, and limited Hebrew.